Robert O. Easton's Lord of Beasts: the Saga of Buffalo Jones papers, 1956-1972
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Robert O. Easton's Lord of Beasts papers, 1956-1972
AZ 313
Easton, Robert Olney
Correspondence, notes, reviews, and background material relating to the composition and publication of the manuscript Lord of Beasts.
.7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Lord of Beasts: the Saga of Buffalo Jones, the story of Charles Jesse Jones, Preserver of the American Bison, was written by Robert O. Easton in collaboration with Mackenzie Brown. It was published by the University of Arizona Press in 1961.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, notes, reviews, and background material relating to the composition and publication of the manuscript.
Access Terms
Jones, Charles Jesse, 1844-1919
Brown, D. Mackenzie (Donald Mackenzie), 1908- -- Correspondence
Kersey, Ralph, 1958-1962 -- Correspondence
Correspondence
Separated Material
Inscribed books received with the collection were removed and cataloged separately.
Container List
- Correspondence: Robert Easton. 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence: Mackenzie Brown. 1956-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Between Robert Easton and Mackenzie Brown. 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Ralph T. Kersey. 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Family of Buffalo Jones. 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: University of Arizona Press. 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Notes, raw material, research. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Notes for chapters. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Buffalo Jones article ideas. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "The Boisterous Ballad of Buffalo Jones," by Robert Easton and Mackenzie Brown, with Gene Caesar. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: Andre Deutsch, Ltd. 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: regarding articles by Ambrose Means. 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Publicity, biographical information, lists of complimentary copies of Lord of Beasts. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Buffalo Jones background material. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Reviews of Lord of Beasts. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Buffalo material. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous material, material for general historical background. (Box 2, Folder 7)